<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-27T16:58:19-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Enze “Alex” Liu</title><subtitle>devlopr-jekyll is a Jekyll Theme Built For Developers</subtitle><author><name>Enze &quot;Alex&quot; Liu</name></author><entry><title type="html">What Is DNS and How To Look Them Up?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/notes/2019/09/27/what_is_DNS_and_how_to_look_them_up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Is DNS and How To Look Them Up?" /><published>2019-09-27T04:05:23-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-27T04:05:23-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/notes/2019/09/27/what_is_DNS_and_how_to_look_them_up</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/notes/2019/09/27/what_is_DNS_and_how_to_look_them_up/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-dns-and-how-to-look-them-up&quot;&gt;What Is DNS and How to Look Them Up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/dns/what-is-dns/&quot;&gt;What Is DNS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dns&quot;&gt;About DNS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-dns&quot;&gt;What’s DNS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Domain Name System (DNS), is the phonebook of the internet. Humans interact with internet via domain names (like “www.example.com”), while browsers interact through Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. DNS translates domain names to IP addresses so taht browers could load the resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each device connected to the internet has an unique IP associated with it, for which could be used to find this device on the internet. DNS servers provide look-ups for the IP addresses and eliminate the need for humans to memorize IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dns-servers&quot;&gt;DNS Servers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-dns-server&quot;&gt;What is DNS Server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machines dedicated to answering DNS queries (Domain Name -&amp;gt; IP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-types-dns-servers&quot;&gt;4 Types DNS Servers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a typical DNS query without any caching, there are four servers that work together to deliver an IP address to the client: recursive resolvers, root nameservers, TLD nameservers, and authoritative nameservers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dns-recursor&quot;&gt;DNS Recursor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recursor (also referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;DNS recursive resolver&lt;/strong&gt;) can be thought of as a librarian who is asked to go find a particular book in the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DNS recursor is a server designed to receive queries from client machines through applications such as web browsers. Typically the recursor is then responsible for making additional requests to satisfy the client’s DNS query.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS recursive resolvers such as Google DNS, OpenDNS, and providers like Comcast all maintain data center installations of DNS recursive resolvers. These resolvers allow for quick and easy queries through optimized clusters of DNS-optimized computer systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;root-nameserver&quot;&gt;Root Nameserver&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The (13) root server is the first step in translating domain names to IP addresses. It can be thought of like an index in a library that points to different racks of books - typically it serves as a reference to other more specific locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A root server accepts a recursive resolver’s query which includes a domain name, and the root nameserver responds by directing the recursive resolver to a TLD nameserver, based on the extension of that domain (.com, .net, .org, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The root nameservers are overseen by a nonprofit called the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN). Note that while there are 13 root nameservers, that doesn’t mean that there are only 13 machines in the root nameserver system. There are 13 types of root nameservers, but there are multiple copies of each one all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tld-nameserver&quot;&gt;TLD Nameserver&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top level domain server (TLD) can be thought of as a specific rack of books in a library. This nameserver is the next step in the search for a specific IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A TLD nameserver maintains information for all the domain names that share a common domain extension, such as .com, .net, or whatever comes after the last dot in a url. For example, a .com TLD nameserver contains information for every website that ends in ‘.com’. If a user was searching for google.com, after receiving a response from a root nameserver, the recursive resolver would then send a query to a .com TLD nameserver, which would respond by pointing to the authoritative nameserver for that domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management of TLD nameservers is handled by the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA), which is a branch of ICANN. The IANA breaks up the TLD servers into two main groups:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generic top-level domains: These are domains that are not country specific, some of the best-known generic TLDs include .com, .org, .net, .edu, and .gov.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Country code top-level domains: These include any domains that are specific to a country or state. Examples include .uk, .us, .ru, and .jp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;authoritative-nameserver&quot;&gt;Authoritative nameserver&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This final nameserver can be thought of as a dictionary on a rack of books, in which a specific name can be translated into its definition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authoritative nameserver is the last stop in the nameserver query. It contains information specific to the domain name it serves (e.g. google.com) and it can provide a recursive resolver with the IP address of that server found in the DNS A record, or if the domain has a CNAME record (alias) it will provide the recursive resolver with an alias domain, at which point the recursive resolver will have to perform a whole new DNS lookup to procure a record from an authoritative nameserver (often an A record containing an IP address).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;additional-nameserver&quot;&gt;Additional nameserver&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth mentioning that in instances where the query is for a &lt;strong&gt;subdomain&lt;/strong&gt; such as foo.example.com or blog.cloudflare.com, an additional nameserver will be added to the sequence after the authoritative nameserver, which is responsible for storing the subdomain’s &lt;strong&gt;CNAME record&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-steps-in-a-dns-lookup&quot;&gt;What are the steps in a DNS lookup?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most situations, DNS is concerned with a domain name being translated into the appropriate IP address. To learn how this process works, it helps to follow the path of a DNS lookup as it travels from a web browser, through the DNS lookup process, and back again. Let’s take a look at the steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Often DNS lookup information will be cached either locally inside the querying computer or remotely in the DNS infrastructure. There are typically 8 steps in a DNS lookup. When DNS information is cached, steps are skipped from the DNS lookup process which makes it quicker. The example below outlines all 8 steps when nothing is cached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 8 steps in a DNS lookup&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A user types ‘example.com’ into a web browser and the query travels into the Internet and is received by a DNS recursive resolver.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The resolver then queries a DNS root nameserver (.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The root server then responds to the resolver with the address of a Top Level Domain (TLD) DNS server (such as .com or .net), which stores the information for its domains. When searching for example.com, our request is pointed toward the .com TLD.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The resolver then makes a request to the .com TLD.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The TLD server then responds with the IP address of the domain’s nameserver, example.com.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lastly, the recursive resolver sends a query to the domain’s nameserver.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The IP address for example.com is then returned to the resolver from the nameserver.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The DNS resolver then responds to the web browser with the IP address of the domain requested initially.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recursive-dns-resolver-vs-recursive-dns-query&quot;&gt;Recursive DNS Resolver vs Recursive DNS Query&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-a-dns-resolver&quot;&gt;What is a DNS resolver?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DNS resolver is the first stop in the DNS lookup, and it is responsible for dealing with the client that made the initial request. The resolver starts the sequence of queries that ultimately leads to a URL being translated into the necessary IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-a-dns-query&quot;&gt;What is a DNS Query?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A DNS query (also known as a DNS request) is a demand for information sent from a user’s computer (DNS client) to a DNS server (typically a DNS recursive resolver).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-are-the-types-of-dns-queries&quot;&gt;What are the types of DNS Queries?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a typical DNS lookup three types of queries occur. By using a combination of these queries, an optimized process for DNS resolution can result in a reduction of distance traveled. In an ideal situation cached record data will be available, allowing a DNS name server to return a non-recursive query.
3 types of DNS queries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recursive query - a DNS client requires that a DNS server will respond to the client with either the requested resource record or an error message if the resolver can’t find the record.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iterative query - If the queried DNS server does not have a match for the query name, it will return a referral to a DNS server authoritative for a lower level of the domain namespace. The DNS client will then make a query to the referral address.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-recursive query - typically this will occur when a DNS resolver client queries a DNS server for a record that it has access to either because it’s authoritative for the record or the record exists inside of its cache.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dns-caching&quot;&gt;DNS Caching&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-dns-caching-where-does-dns-caching-occur&quot;&gt;What is DNS caching? Where does DNS caching occur?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of caching is to temporarily stored data in a location that results in improvements in performance and reliability for data requests. DNS caching involves storing data closer to the requesting client so that the DNS query can be resolved earlier and additional queries further down the DNS lookup chain can be avoided, thereby improving load times and reducing bandwidth/CPU consumption. DNS data can be cached in a variety of locations, each of which will store DNS records for a set amount of time determined by a &lt;strong&gt;time-to-live (TTL)&lt;/strong&gt;. This time limit is set explicitly in the DNS records for each site. Typically the TTL is in the 24-48 hour range. A TTL is necessary because web servers occasionally change their IP addresses, so resolvers can’t serve the same IP from the cache indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;browser-dns-caching&quot;&gt;Browser DNS caching&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern web browsers are designed by default to cache DNS records for a set amount of time. the purpose here is obvious; the closer the DNS caching occurs to the web browser, the fewer processing steps must be taken in order to check the cache and make the correct requests to an IP address. When a request is made for a DNS record, the browser cache is the first location checked for the requested record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;operating-system-os-level-dns-caching&quot;&gt;Operating system (OS) level DNS caching&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The operating system level DNS resolver is the second and last local stop before a DNS query leaves your machine. The process inside your operating system that is designed to handle this query is commonly called a “stub resolver” or DNS client. When a stub resolver gets a request from an application, it first checks its own cache to see if it has the record. If it does not, it then sends a DNS query (with a recursive flag set), outside the local network to a DNS recursive resolver inside the Internet service provider (ISP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the recursive resolver inside the ISP receives a DNS query, like all previous steps, it will also check to see if the requested host-to-IP-address translation is already stored inside its local persistence layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recursive resolver also has additional functionality depending on the types of records it has in its cache:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the resolver does not have the &lt;strong&gt;A records&lt;/strong&gt;, but does have the &lt;strong&gt;NS records&lt;/strong&gt; for the authoritative nameservers, it will query those name servers directly, bypassing several steps in the DNS query. This shortcut prevents lookups from the root and .com nameservers (in our search for example.com) and helps the resolution of the DNS query occur more quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the resolver does not have the NS records, it will send a query to the TLD servers (.com in our case), skipping the root server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the unlikely event that the resolver does not have records pointing to the TLD servers, it will then query the root servers. This event typically occurs after a DNS cache has been purged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dns-records&quot;&gt;DNS Records&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-dns-record&quot;&gt;What is a DNS record?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNS records (aka zone files) are instructions that live in authoritative DNS servers and provide information about a domain including what IP address is associated with that domain and how to handle requests for that domain. These records consist of a series of text files written in what is known as DNS syntax. DNS syntax is just a string of characters used as commands which tell the DNS server what to do. All DNS records also have a ‘TTL’, which stands for time-to-live, and indicates how often a DNS server will refresh that record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-most-common-types-of-dns-record&quot;&gt;What are the most common types of DNS record?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A record - The record that holds the IP address of a domain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CNAME record - Forwards one domain or subdomain to another domain, does NOT provide an IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MX record - Directs mail to an email server.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TXT record - Lets an admin store text notes in the record.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NS record - Stores the name server for a DNS entry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SOA record - Stores admin information about a domain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SRV record - Specifies a port for specific services.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PTR record - Provides a domain name in reverse-lookups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-record&quot;&gt;A Record&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘A’ stands for ‘address’ and this is the most fundamental type of DNS record, it indicates the IP address of a given domain. For example if you pull the DNS records of google.com, the ‘A’ record currently returns an IP address of: 172.217.5.78. ‘A’ records only hold Ipv4 addresses, if the site has a Ipv6 address, it will instead use an ‘AAAA’ record&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of an A record:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;example.com&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;record type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;value&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;TTL&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;@&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;12.34.56.78&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;14400&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘@’ here indicates that this is a record for the root domain, and the ‘14400’ value is the TTL (Time To Live), listed in seconds. The default TTL for A records is 14400 seconds. This means that if an A record gets updated, it takes 240 minutes (14400 seconds) to take effect (because after 14400 secs you will refetch).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of websites only have one A record, but &lt;strong&gt;it’s possible to have several A records&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cname-record&quot;&gt;CNAME record&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘canonical name’ record is used in lieu of an A record, when a domain or subdomain is an alias of another domain. Imagine a scavenger hunt where each clue points to another clue, and the final clue points to the treasure. A domain with a CNAME record is like a clue which can point you to another clue (another domain with a CNAME record) or to the treasure (a domain with an A record). For example, suppose www.example.com has a CNAME record with a value of ‘example.com’ (without the ‘www’). This means when a DNS server hits the DNS records for www.example.com, it actually triggers another DNS lookup to example.com, returning example.com’s IP address. In this case we would say that example.com is the canonical name (or true name) of blog.example.com. All CNAME records must point to a domain, never to an IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, when sites have subdomains such as blog.example.com or shop.example.com, those subdomains will have CNAME records which point to a root domain (example.com). This way if the IP of the host changes, only the DNS A record for the root domain needs to be updated and all the CNAME records will follow along with whatever changes are made to the root.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A frequent misconception is that a CNAME record must always resolve to the same website as the domain it points to, but this is not the case. The CNAME record only points the client to the same IP address as the root domain. Once the client hits that IP address, the web server will still handle the URL accordingly. So for instance, blog.example.com might have a CNAME that points to example.com, directing the client to example.com’s IP address. But when the client actually connects to that IP address, the web server will look at the URL, see that it’s blog.example.com, and deliver the blog page rather than the home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of a CNAME record:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;example.com&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;record type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;value&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;TTL&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;@&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;CNAME&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;is an alias of example.com&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;32600&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example you can see that blog.example.com points to example.com, and assuming it’s based on our example A record we know that it will eventually resolve to the IP address 12.34.56.78.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mx-record&quot;&gt;MX record?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the ‘mail exchange’ record, and it directs email to a mail server. The MX record indicates how email messages should be routed in accordance with Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP, the standard protocol for all email.) Like CNAME records, an MX record must always point to another domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of an MX record:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;example.com&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;record type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;value&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;TTL&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;@&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;MX&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;10 mailhost.example.com&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;45000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;@&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;MX&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;20 mailhost2.example.com&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;45000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The numbers before the domains in the value entries for these MX records indicate preference; the server will always try mailhost1 first because 10 is lower than 20, in the result of a message send failure, the server will default to mailhost2.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Enze Liu</name></author><category term="notes" /><summary type="html">What Is DNS and How to Look Them Up Reference: What Is DNS? About DNS What’s DNS The Domain Name System (DNS), is the phonebook of the internet. Humans interact with internet via domain names (like “www.example.com”), while browsers interact through Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. DNS translates domain names to IP addresses so taht browers could load the resources. Each device connected to the internet has an unique IP associated with it, for which could be used to find this device on the internet. DNS servers provide look-ups for the IP addresses and eliminate the need for humans to memorize IP addresses. DNS Servers What is DNS Server Machines dedicated to answering DNS queries (Domain Name -&amp;gt; IP). 4 Types DNS Servers In a typical DNS query without any caching, there are four servers that work together to deliver an IP address to the client: recursive resolvers, root nameservers, TLD nameservers, and authoritative nameservers. DNS Recursor The recursor (also referred to as the DNS recursive resolver) can be thought of as a librarian who is asked to go find a particular book in the library. The DNS recursor is a server designed to receive queries from client machines through applications such as web browsers. Typically the recursor is then responsible for making additional requests to satisfy the client’s DNS query. DNS recursive resolvers such as Google DNS, OpenDNS, and providers like Comcast all maintain data center installations of DNS recursive resolvers. These resolvers allow for quick and easy queries through optimized clusters of DNS-optimized computer systems. Root Nameserver The (13) root server is the first step in translating domain names to IP addresses. It can be thought of like an index in a library that points to different racks of books - typically it serves as a reference to other more specific locations. A root server accepts a recursive resolver’s query which includes a domain name, and the root nameserver responds by directing the recursive resolver to a TLD nameserver, based on the extension of that domain (.com, .net, .org, etc.). The root nameservers are overseen by a nonprofit called the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN). Note that while there are 13 root nameservers, that doesn’t mean that there are only 13 machines in the root nameserver system. There are 13 types of root nameservers, but there are multiple copies of each one all over the world. TLD Nameserver The top level domain server (TLD) can be thought of as a specific rack of books in a library. This nameserver is the next step in the search for a specific IP address. A TLD nameserver maintains information for all the domain names that share a common domain extension, such as .com, .net, or whatever comes after the last dot in a url. For example, a .com TLD nameserver contains information for every website that ends in ‘.com’. If a user was searching for google.com, after receiving a response from a root nameserver, the recursive resolver would then send a query to a .com TLD nameserver, which would respond by pointing to the authoritative nameserver for that domain. Management of TLD nameservers is handled by the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA), which is a branch of ICANN. The IANA breaks up the TLD servers into two main groups: Generic top-level domains: These are domains that are not country specific, some of the best-known generic TLDs include .com, .org, .net, .edu, and .gov. Country code top-level domains: These include any domains that are specific to a country or state. Examples include .uk, .us, .ru, and .jp Authoritative nameserver This final nameserver can be thought of as a dictionary on a rack of books, in which a specific name can be translated into its definition. The authoritative nameserver is the last stop in the nameserver query. It contains information specific to the domain name it serves (e.g. google.com) and it can provide a recursive resolver with the IP address of that server found in the DNS A record, or if the domain has a CNAME record (alias) it will provide the recursive resolver with an alias domain, at which point the recursive resolver will have to perform a whole new DNS lookup to procure a record from an authoritative nameserver (often an A record containing an IP address). Additional nameserver It’s worth mentioning that in instances where the query is for a subdomain such as foo.example.com or blog.cloudflare.com, an additional nameserver will be added to the sequence after the authoritative nameserver, which is responsible for storing the subdomain’s CNAME record. What are the steps in a DNS lookup? For most situations, DNS is concerned with a domain name being translated into the appropriate IP address. To learn how this process works, it helps to follow the path of a DNS lookup as it travels from a web browser, through the DNS lookup process, and back again. Let’s take a look at the steps. Note: Often DNS lookup information will be cached either locally inside the querying computer or remotely in the DNS infrastructure. There are typically 8 steps in a DNS lookup. When DNS information is cached, steps are skipped from the DNS lookup process which makes it quicker. The example below outlines all 8 steps when nothing is cached. The 8 steps in a DNS lookup: A user types ‘example.com’ into a web browser and the query travels into the Internet and is received by a DNS recursive resolver. The resolver then queries a DNS root nameserver (.). The root server then responds to the resolver with the address of a Top Level Domain (TLD) DNS server (such as .com or .net), which stores the information for its domains. When searching for example.com, our request is pointed toward the .com TLD. The resolver then makes a request to the .com TLD. The TLD server then responds with the IP address of the domain’s nameserver, example.com. Lastly, the recursive resolver sends a query to the domain’s nameserver. The IP address for example.com is then returned to the resolver from the nameserver. The DNS resolver then responds to the web browser with the IP address of the domain requested initially. Recursive DNS Resolver vs Recursive DNS Query What is a DNS resolver? The DNS resolver is the first stop in the DNS lookup, and it is responsible for dealing with the client that made the initial request. The resolver starts the sequence of queries that ultimately leads to a URL being translated into the necessary IP address. What is a DNS Query? A DNS query (also known as a DNS request) is a demand for information sent from a user’s computer (DNS client) to a DNS server (typically a DNS recursive resolver). What are the types of DNS Queries? In a typical DNS lookup three types of queries occur. By using a combination of these queries, an optimized process for DNS resolution can result in a reduction of distance traveled. In an ideal situation cached record data will be available, allowing a DNS name server to return a non-recursive query. 3 types of DNS queries: Recursive query - a DNS client requires that a DNS server will respond to the client with either the requested resource record or an error message if the resolver can’t find the record. Iterative query - If the queried DNS server does not have a match for the query name, it will return a referral to a DNS server authoritative for a lower level of the domain namespace. The DNS client will then make a query to the referral address. Non-recursive query - typically this will occur when a DNS resolver client queries a DNS server for a record that it has access to either because it’s authoritative for the record or the record exists inside of its cache. DNS Caching What is DNS caching? Where does DNS caching occur? The purpose of caching is to temporarily stored data in a location that results in improvements in performance and reliability for data requests. DNS caching involves storing data closer to the requesting client so that the DNS query can be resolved earlier and additional queries further down the DNS lookup chain can be avoided, thereby improving load times and reducing bandwidth/CPU consumption. DNS data can be cached in a variety of locations, each of which will store DNS records for a set amount of time determined by a time-to-live (TTL). This time limit is set explicitly in the DNS records for each site. Typically the TTL is in the 24-48 hour range. A TTL is necessary because web servers occasionally change their IP addresses, so resolvers can’t serve the same IP from the cache indefinitely. Browser DNS caching Modern web browsers are designed by default to cache DNS records for a set amount of time. the purpose here is obvious; the closer the DNS caching occurs to the web browser, the fewer processing steps must be taken in order to check the cache and make the correct requests to an IP address. When a request is made for a DNS record, the browser cache is the first location checked for the requested record. Operating system (OS) level DNS caching The operating system level DNS resolver is the second and last local stop before a DNS query leaves your machine. The process inside your operating system that is designed to handle this query is commonly called a “stub resolver” or DNS client. When a stub resolver gets a request from an application, it first checks its own cache to see if it has the record. If it does not, it then sends a DNS query (with a recursive flag set), outside the local network to a DNS recursive resolver inside the Internet service provider (ISP). When the recursive resolver inside the ISP receives a DNS query, like all previous steps, it will also check to see if the requested host-to-IP-address translation is already stored inside its local persistence layer. The recursive resolver also has additional functionality depending on the types of records it has in its cache: If the resolver does not have the A records, but does have the NS records for the authoritative nameservers, it will query those name servers directly, bypassing several steps in the DNS query. This shortcut prevents lookups from the root and .com nameservers (in our search for example.com) and helps the resolution of the DNS query occur more quickly. If the resolver does not have the NS records, it will send a query to the TLD servers (.com in our case), skipping the root server. In the unlikely event that the resolver does not have records pointing to the TLD servers, it will then query the root servers. This event typically occurs after a DNS cache has been purged. DNS Records What is a DNS record? DNS records (aka zone files) are instructions that live in authoritative DNS servers and provide information about a domain including what IP address is associated with that domain and how to handle requests for that domain. These records consist of a series of text files written in what is known as DNS syntax. DNS syntax is just a string of characters used as commands which tell the DNS server what to do. All DNS records also have a ‘TTL’, which stands for time-to-live, and indicates how often a DNS server will refresh that record. What are the most common types of DNS record? A record - The record that holds the IP address of a domain. CNAME record - Forwards one domain or subdomain to another domain, does NOT provide an IP address. MX record - Directs mail to an email server. TXT record - Lets an admin store text notes in the record. NS record - Stores the name server for a DNS entry. SOA record - Stores admin information about a domain. SRV record - Specifies a port for specific services. PTR record - Provides a domain name in reverse-lookups. A Record The ‘A’ stands for ‘address’ and this is the most fundamental type of DNS record, it indicates the IP address of a given domain. For example if you pull the DNS records of google.com, the ‘A’ record currently returns an IP address of: 172.217.5.78. ‘A’ records only hold Ipv4 addresses, if the site has a Ipv6 address, it will instead use an ‘AAAA’ record Example of an A record: example.com record type value TTL @ A 12.34.56.78 14400 The ‘@’ here indicates that this is a record for the root domain, and the ‘14400’ value is the TTL (Time To Live), listed in seconds. The default TTL for A records is 14400 seconds. This means that if an A record gets updated, it takes 240 minutes (14400 seconds) to take effect (because after 14400 secs you will refetch). The vast majority of websites only have one A record, but it’s possible to have several A records. CNAME record The ‘canonical name’ record is used in lieu of an A record, when a domain or subdomain is an alias of another domain. Imagine a scavenger hunt where each clue points to another clue, and the final clue points to the treasure. A domain with a CNAME record is like a clue which can point you to another clue (another domain with a CNAME record) or to the treasure (a domain with an A record). For example, suppose www.example.com has a CNAME record with a value of ‘example.com’ (without the ‘www’). This means when a DNS server hits the DNS records for www.example.com, it actually triggers another DNS lookup to example.com, returning example.com’s IP address. In this case we would say that example.com is the canonical name (or true name) of blog.example.com. All CNAME records must point to a domain, never to an IP address. Oftentimes, when sites have subdomains such as blog.example.com or shop.example.com, those subdomains will have CNAME records which point to a root domain (example.com). This way if the IP of the host changes, only the DNS A record for the root domain needs to be updated and all the CNAME records will follow along with whatever changes are made to the root. A frequent misconception is that a CNAME record must always resolve to the same website as the domain it points to, but this is not the case. The CNAME record only points the client to the same IP address as the root domain. Once the client hits that IP address, the web server will still handle the URL accordingly. So for instance, blog.example.com might have a CNAME that points to example.com, directing the client to example.com’s IP address. But when the client actually connects to that IP address, the web server will look at the URL, see that it’s blog.example.com, and deliver the blog page rather than the home page. Example of a CNAME record: example.com record type value TTL @ CNAME is an alias of example.com 32600 In this example you can see that blog.example.com points to example.com, and assuming it’s based on our example A record we know that it will eventually resolve to the IP address 12.34.56.78. MX record? This is the ‘mail exchange’ record, and it directs email to a mail server. The MX record indicates how email messages should be routed in accordance with Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP, the standard protocol for all email.) Like CNAME records, an MX record must always point to another domain. Example of an MX record: example.com record type value TTL @ MX 10 mailhost.example.com 45000 @ MX 20 mailhost2.example.com 45000 The numbers before the domains in the value entries for these MX records indicate preference; the server will always try mailhost1 first because 10 is lower than 20, in the result of a message send failure, the server will default to mailhost2.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Read Scientific Literature</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/notes/2019/09/26/how_to_read_scientific_literature/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Read Scientific Literature" /><published>2019-09-26T02:05:23-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-26T02:05:23-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/notes/2019/09/26/how_to_read_scientific_literature</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/notes/2019/09/26/how_to_read_scientific_literature/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-read-scientific-literature&quot;&gt;How To Read Scientific Literature&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/class/ee384m/Handouts/HowtoReadPaper.pdf&quot;&gt;How to Read a Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.columbia.edu/~hgs/netbib/efficientReading.pdf&quot;&gt;Efficient Reading of Papers in Science and Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://people.cs.pitt.edu/~litman/courses/cs2710/papers/howtoreadacspaper.pdf&quot;&gt;How to Read a Computer Science Research Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.jhu.edu/~jason/advice/how-to-read-a-paper.html&quot;&gt;How to Read a Technical Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-paper-reading&quot;&gt;Why Paper Reading?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers must read papers for several reasons: to review them for a conference or a class, to keep current in their field, or for a literature survey of a new field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-pass-approach&quot;&gt;Three-Pass Approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should read the paper multiple passes, instead of starting at the beginning and plowing all the way to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-pass&quot;&gt;First Pass&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of first pass is to have a general idea about the paper. More specifically, you should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carefully&lt;/strong&gt; read the title, abstract, and introduction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the section and sub-section headings, but ignore everything else&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the conclusions
At the end of the first pass, you should be able to answer the following questions:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category: What type of paper is this? Theoratical (describes a theory or algorithm or provides a mathematical proof)? Engineering (an implementation &amp;amp;&amp;amp; evauluation of an algorithm, or part or all of a computer system or application)? Empirical paper (experiment designed to test some hypothesis)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Topic: What problems does this paper address? Are they important and why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Context: Which other papers is it related to? Which theoretical bases were used to analyze the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contributions: What are the paper’s main contributions?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Correctness: Do the assumptions appear to be valid?
Depending on this information, you might choose not to keep reading. This could because it is not interesting, the assumptions are not valid, or you don’t have enough background knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;second-pass&quot;&gt;Second Pass&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grasp the paper’s content, but not the detail. In the second pass, read the paper with greater care, but ignore details such as proofs. It helps to jot down the key points, or to make comments in the margins, as you read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the introductions carefully.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What assumptions do they rely on?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do the authors present evidence that they know why they are doing this piece of research?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do they have an idea of the larger picture?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the definitions and theroms carefully.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the methods section carefully&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pay special attention to graphs. Are the axes properly labeled? Are results shown with error bars, so that conclusions are statistically significant?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mark relevant unread references for further reading. 
After the second pass, you should be able to summarize the main thrust of the paper, with supporting evidence, to someone else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-pass&quot;&gt;Third Pass&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to the third pass is to attempt to virtually re-implement the paper: that is, making the same assumptions as the authors, re-create the work. You should identify and challenge every assumption in every statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doing-literature-survey&quot;&gt;Doing Literature Survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Google Scholar to find three to five &lt;strong&gt;recent papers&lt;/strong&gt; in the area. Do one pass on each paper to get a sense of the work, then read their related work
sections. You will find a thumbnail summary of the recent work, and perhaps, if you are lucky, a pointer to a recent survey paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Otherwise, in the second step, find shared citations and repeated author names in the bibliography. These are the key papers and researchers in that area. Download the key papers and set them aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The third step is to go to the website for these top conferences and look through their recent proceedings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;indicators-of-a-good-research-paper&quot;&gt;Indicators of A Good Research Paper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The problem the paper addresses is clearly stated, both in the abstract and early on in the paper itself. The technical importance and broader impacts of the paper are described.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The paper includes a clear description of the experiment, system or theory the
problem addresses. This is usually the second section of the paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The paper describes and analyzes the results of the work described.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The authors have some sound, non-trivial ideas for future work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions-to-ask-when-reading-a-paper&quot;&gt;Questions To Ask When Reading A Paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;assumptions&quot;&gt;Assumptions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do their results rely on any assumptions about trends or environments?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are the author’s claims reasonable and realistic?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;methods&quot;&gt;Methods&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the approach clearly described? Can you outline the steps or summarize the approach?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did they address the problem stated earlier in the paper/measure what they claim?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can they explain what they observed?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did they have adequate controls/require unreasonable amounts of human guidance?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Were tests carried out in a standard/objective way?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do the conclusions follow logically from the observations?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What other conclusions or correlations are there in the data that they did not point out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Enze Liu</name></author><category term="notes" /><summary type="html">How To Read Scientific Literature References: How to Read a Paper Efficient Reading of Papers in Science and Technology How to Read a Computer Science Research Paper How to Read a Technical Paper Why Paper Reading? Researchers must read papers for several reasons: to review them for a conference or a class, to keep current in their field, or for a literature survey of a new field. Three-Pass Approach You should read the paper multiple passes, instead of starting at the beginning and plowing all the way to the end. First Pass The purpose of first pass is to have a general idea about the paper. More specifically, you should: Carefully read the title, abstract, and introduction Read the section and sub-section headings, but ignore everything else Read the conclusions At the end of the first pass, you should be able to answer the following questions: Category: What type of paper is this? Theoratical (describes a theory or algorithm or provides a mathematical proof)? Engineering (an implementation &amp;amp;&amp;amp; evauluation of an algorithm, or part or all of a computer system or application)? Empirical paper (experiment designed to test some hypothesis)? Topic: What problems does this paper address? Are they important and why? Context: Which other papers is it related to? Which theoretical bases were used to analyze the problem? Contributions: What are the paper’s main contributions? Correctness: Do the assumptions appear to be valid? Depending on this information, you might choose not to keep reading. This could because it is not interesting, the assumptions are not valid, or you don’t have enough background knowledge. Second Pass Grasp the paper’s content, but not the detail. In the second pass, read the paper with greater care, but ignore details such as proofs. It helps to jot down the key points, or to make comments in the margins, as you read. Read the introductions carefully. What assumptions do they rely on? Do the authors present evidence that they know why they are doing this piece of research? Do they have an idea of the larger picture? Read the definitions and theroms carefully. Read the methods section carefully Pay special attention to graphs. Are the axes properly labeled? Are results shown with error bars, so that conclusions are statistically significant? Mark relevant unread references for further reading. After the second pass, you should be able to summarize the main thrust of the paper, with supporting evidence, to someone else. Third Pass The key to the third pass is to attempt to virtually re-implement the paper: that is, making the same assumptions as the authors, re-create the work. You should identify and challenge every assumption in every statement. Doing Literature Survey Use Google Scholar to find three to five recent papers in the area. Do one pass on each paper to get a sense of the work, then read their related work sections. You will find a thumbnail summary of the recent work, and perhaps, if you are lucky, a pointer to a recent survey paper. Otherwise, in the second step, find shared citations and repeated author names in the bibliography. These are the key papers and researchers in that area. Download the key papers and set them aside. The third step is to go to the website for these top conferences and look through their recent proceedings. Indicators of A Good Research Paper The problem the paper addresses is clearly stated, both in the abstract and early on in the paper itself. The technical importance and broader impacts of the paper are described. The paper includes a clear description of the experiment, system or theory the problem addresses. This is usually the second section of the paper. The paper describes and analyzes the results of the work described. The authors have some sound, non-trivial ideas for future work. Questions To Ask When Reading A Paper Assumptions Do their results rely on any assumptions about trends or environments? Are the author’s claims reasonable and realistic? Methods Is the approach clearly described? Can you outline the steps or summarize the approach? Did they address the problem stated earlier in the paper/measure what they claim? Can they explain what they observed? Did they have adequate controls/require unreasonable amounts of human guidance? Were tests carried out in a standard/objective way? Conclusions Do the conclusions follow logically from the observations? What other conclusions or correlations are there in the data that they did not point out?</summary></entry></feed>